ANIRUDH EMMADI

emmadi.anirudh@gmail.com | 469-403-1726 | 2328 Boatman Drive, Little Elm, TX | linkedin.com/in/anirudhemmadi/ | anirudhemmadi.com

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic and creative software developer with over 2 years of professional experience in producing robust code and managing clientele. Initiative-taking self-starter who can easily adapt to rapid change in environments and projects. Improved code efficiency at Toucan AI by 30%, shipped code being used in over 100,000 projects at MLH, built applications that impact over 20,000 students at ACM, and managed clients from around the world as a software freelancer.

EXPERIENCE

Open Source Engineer, Major League Hacking (MLH)

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

- Collaborated among a team of 6 people in the development of Docsify.js a documentation rendering tool that is being used by over 15,000 projects.
- Developed a microservice that renders Github readme files into full fledged documentation using NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, and AWS by following SCRUM and AGILE methodology.

Software Engineer Intern, Toucan AI

May 2020 - Aug 2020

- Performed user metric data collection and data analysis to generate data tables for internal use with Python and MongoDB, helping increase revenue by 10%.
- Developed and managed a RESTful API, later optimizing it with a run-time of 300 milliseconds.
- Implemented visualization of user data in user and admin dashboards using React, improving user interactivity by 13%.
- Experienced a fast-paced Startup lifestyle with a rapidly changing environment.

Software Engineer Intern, Bundil

Feb 2020 - Apr 2020

- Developed, managed and maintained back-end services like REST API, and authentication middleware, using Typescript, Angular, and MongoDB.
- Built production builds using pipelines with automated deployment to Google Cloud Platform, reducing deployment time by 20%.

Software Engineer, Association of Computing Machinery (ACM)

Sep 2019 - May 2020

- Built applications that impacted over 20,000 students from the UT Dallas community.
- Mentored undergraduate freshman and helped them succeed in college by guiding them at every stage.

Tech Consultant, Freelancer

Jul 2016 - Jan 2020

- Managed over 50 clients around the world and consulted regarding Linux servers and scalable infrastructure solutions.
- Developed scripts that were primarily deployed in Docker containers.
- Performed cost analysis for clients to determine the best server providers for the project

PROJECTS

CourseBook-API

- Built an REST API that serves course info and enrollment data from UT Dallas using Python, Selenium, Flask, MongoDB, and Heroku.
- Optimized code by using advanced algorithms, and smart caching to parse and serve the data in under 600 milliseconds.

Kanna Bot

• Discord bot that calls various API's from Reddit, Riot, CoinMarketCap, and Epic Games to output and visualize data using NodeJS, and DigitalOcean VPS. While it was active, the bot had been installed in over 100 servers.

*i*Cycle

• Mobile application that determines if an scanned item is safe to recycle or not using Java and Android Studio.

HONORS AND AWARDS

- OP: Live Hackathon First Place Winner (2019) For developing best algorithm to match esports players and recruiters
- HackUTD Second Place Winner (2019) Built and demoed a delivery service app in front of 500 developers
- SevenTablets Hackathon Third Place Winner (2019) Developed application that sends text messages over a blockchain
- Academic Excellence Scholarship (AES) Given to top 10% of students who have shown immense potential

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, NodeJS, React, MongoDB, Python, Flask, Java, C++, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, Markdown Technologies: Git, Linux, Unix, REST API, GraphQL, Firebase, AWS, Heroku, Docker, Kubernetes Tools: GitHub, Kan-ban Board, Postman, Trello, Jira, Command Line, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Slack Soft: Entrepreneurship, Mentorship, Project Management, Growth Mindset, Adaptability, Communication Skills

EDUCATION